Ethan Peters

Brighton

Flat 4 Old Stores, Berwick, Brighton, BN26 6TA

07760 433 250 ethanjackpeters@hotmail.com

Skills

With 10 years' experience in the automotive industry, I am looking to commence a new career journey to broaden my professional horizons. As a punctual and creative individual, I excel in problem solving and thrive both independently and within a team. Possessing strong communication skills, I am open to learning and adaptable to direction. My extensive background in the automotive sector has equipped me with a solid foundation. I bring a unique blend of technical expertise, problem solving acumen and adaptability to contribute effectively to a different industry. I am eager to apply my skills and wish to be challenged further in a new professional field.

Experience

Strafford Cars / Vehicle Technician

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT, BRIGHTON

Duties within this role include diagnosing and repairing sales vehicles this involves both remote and workshop-based repairs. Remote work includes liaising with customers to best fulfil their requirements and independently diagnosing and repairing the vehicles. Workshop based duties involve managing all pre-sale preparation for vehicles. This includes identifying and organising required bodywork, inspecting and rectifying any mechanical faults, arranging with third-party companies for parts and quotes and liaising with other departments regarding vehicle preparation status. Mechanical repairs cover major warranty work, servicing and general maintenance.

Strafford Service Centre / Workshop Technician

NOVEMBER 2016 - 2020, BRIGHTON

Day to day activities include diagnosing and repairing vehicles, liaising with third-party companies for parts and quotes, drawing up estimates for customers whilst always adapting to the newest equipment and

technologies. This job is also heavily customer service based, building good rapport with our customers, especially when occasionally working in the hire and sales offices.

Brighton & Hove City Council / Vehicle Technician ApprenticeJANUARY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016, BRIGHTON

During my time here, I maintained and repaired the council's fleet of vehicles and agricultural machinery whilst also studying at college where I gained concrete knowledge and skills.

Portobello Market / Sales Assistant

2013-2015, LONDON

Whilst at college, I worked on the weekends as a sales assistant on a busy stall in Portobello Market in London. This enhanced my customer service and people skills allowing me to confidently approach people in a welcoming manner.

Black Rock Tyres / Tyre Fitter

2013, BRIGHTON

At age 16, this was my first job in the automotive industry which built the foundation of my mechanical career.

Education

Plumpton College

2016, Brighton

Agricultural Machinery Level 2

City College

2013-2015, Brighton

Vehicle Maintenance Level 3

Vehicle Maintenance Level 2

Plumpton College

2011-2013, Brighton

Vehicle Maintenance Level 1

Sussex Central YMCA

2011

Systematic Cycle Check Level 1 (Pass)

Push Bike Mechanics Level 1 (Pass)

Hove Park School

2007-2013, Brighton

Mathematics, English Literature, English Language, Product Design, Core Science, Additional Science

Skills & Awards

- Award for 'Top Motor Vehicle Student in Brighton & Hove' in 2013
- Very skilled in light vehicle maintenance
- Full clean UK driving license

Hobbies & Interests

- Computing Technologies
- Gaming
- Motorsport

References available upon request.